Marco Risi

linkedin.com/in/risi-marco/ github.com/marcorisi marcorisi.dev

I am a technical leader experienced in building and scaling high-performing distributed remote tech teams.

I love working in and building challenging, diverse and healthy environments, where I can learn and grow by working with talented and passionate people.

Work Experience

CTO Everli Aug 2015-Present

Verona, Italy (Fully Remote)

- Built and scaled a fully remote international tech team (remote since Feb 2017, now 70 Engineers, 10+ Nationalities)
- Led the product internationalization process: from Supermercato24 to Everli, from 1 country (IT) to 4 (IT, PL, CZ, FR)
- Led a team that built products that generates 100M+ GMV yearly, has 10K+ of daily users, with 50+ NPS
- Defined and implemented a growth framework for engineers (Engineering Ladder)
- Started a DevOps culture transformation (AWS & GCP adoption, DORA4 measurements)
- Responsible for the Organizational Design (teams structure iterated multiple times during the company growth)
- Run technical due diligence for M&A or fundraising (Series A, B, C)
- Defined, together with the Leadership Team, the company strategy, goals, priorities and roadmap

Back End Engineer Everli Jan 2015–Jul 2015

Verona, Italy

- Designed the architecture and defined the apps technology stack (*Laravel, AngularJS, Redis, MySQL, Jenkins, Bootstrap*)
- Built the first version and responsible for the logistic platform (dispatcher system, shopper app, internal tools)
- Helped with the recruitment of the first employees (not only tech)
- Worked with other teams to validate the product market fit

Front End Developer Paperlit 2014–2015

Verona, Italy

- Built the self-provisioning backoffice module that let customer autonomously configure their own app (*Polymer, Firebase*)
- Entirely refactored the web reader app (AngularJS)
- Build a Samsung Smart TV streaming video app (AngularJS, SmartTV SDK)

Full Stack Developer MHT Servizi 2012–2014

Verona, Italy

- Worked on several projects (multi-vendor eCommerce, custom CRM systems, smart lamps remote management) with many different technologies (*Python, jQuery, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, PHP Zend, ...*)
- Introduced git to the organization

Education and Certifications

•	M.Sc. Computer Engineering, University of Pavia, Italy, 110/110 cum laude.	2011
•	B.Sc. Computer Engineering, University of Pavia (Mantova site), Italy, 110/110 cum laude.	2009

• **High School Diploma, Computer specialization,** Institute "Alle Stimate", Verona, Italy, 110/110

2006

Interests